JOBAER ISLAM KHAN

n Dhaka, Bangladesh

****+8801689064469

✓ Jobaer.iitdu@gmail.com

m www.linkedin.com/in/jobaer-islam-khan

jobaerkhan.github.io





CAREER SUMMARY

Enthusiastic technical professional having excellent technical skills, communication skills, and goal-focused offering more than 5 years of experience in Software industry. I excel in different popular languages (ASP.NET Core, C#), Database (SQL Server, MySQL, Redshift, DynamoDB, Oracle), DevOps and JavaScript (AngularJS, Angular).



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Senior Software Engineer | Aan-Nahl Software Limited, Dhaka, Bangladesh SEPTEMBER, 2018 – PRESENT

- Project specific requirement analysis and communication with clients
- Define application architectures, database structures, user interface layouts, workflows, control processes and interfaces
- Fixing bugs, implementing change request of clients and enhancements of existing projects
- Supervision of trainee and junior developers
- Developed Customer Email Delivery System and Telemarketing Management system for inhouse telemarketing department
- Developing B2B application for agency and business directory

Software Engineer | IQVIA, Dhaka, Bangladesh

OCTOBER, 2016 - AUGUST, 2018

- Project specific requirement analysis, communication with team lead and project manager
- Participated on essential R&D tasks to integrate new technologies as per requirements
- Web application development using .NET, C#, SQL Server, Oracle, Angular and JavaScript
- Creating BI reports using Power BI and Tableau
- Developed HCRS(Health care regulatory system) for a reputed multinational company

Software Engineer | The Jaxara IT Ltd., Dhaka, Bangladesh

JULY, 2015-SEPTEMBER, 2016

- Development of Web applications using ASP.NET Web API, Entity Framework, SQL, Angularjs
- Development of Cloud based applications using cutting edge technologies like Amazon Web Services (DynamoDb, Lambda, EC2, S3, Redshift, RDS)
- Optimized and refactor existing components and Maintain standard coding convention and coding quality
- Performed Research and Development into the very latest in Internet-based technologies, methodologies, architectures and industry trends
- Developed a highly scalable healthcare data management application platform

Software Engineer | Mercantile Systems Limited, Dhaka, Bangladesh

MAY, 2014-JUNE, 2015

- Analyze, design and develop web and desktop applications based on specifications
- Product documentations
- Developed Sales and Inventory Management System (SIMS)
- Developed Transport monitoring system (TMS)
- Developed and enhanced existing Insurance management system (IMS)
- Developed Bank Statement Reconciliation software for in-house use



EDUCATION

Master's of Science in Software Engineering | University of Dhaka

JANUARY, 2013 - MAY, 2014

Major Courses:

- Research Methodology
- Distributed Software Engineering
- Secure Software Design and Programming

Bachelor's in Information Technology | University of Dhaka

FEBRUARY, 2009 – DECEMBER, 2012

Major Courses:

- Object oriented concept
- Design Patterns
- Software testing and quality assurance
- Software Design and Analysis
- Software Project Management
- Artificial intelligence

Higher Secondary School Certificate | Faujdarhat Cadet College

PASSING YEAR, 2008



PUBLICATIONS

- Identifying Overloaded Servers and Managing Dynamic Placement of Virtual machines in Cloud, Apr 2016, Journal of Computer Applications (0975 8887)
- An Attribute Selection Process for Software Defect Prediction, May 2014, Electronics & Vision (ICIEV), 2014 International Conference on. IEEE



- Programming & Scripting Language Skills: C#, C/C++, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Familiar with Python
- DBMS Skills: SQL Server, MySQL, Redshift, DynamoDB, Oracle
- DevOps Skills: Docker, Jenkins, AWS, Microsoft Azure
- Frameworks: Microsoft .NET Framework, ASP.NET Core, ASP.NET MVC 5, Entity Framework, Angularjs, Angular 4/6, Angular Material
- **Development Tools:** Microsoft Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Bluefish, SQL server management studio, Aginity Workbench for Amazon Redshift
- **Designing Tools:** Rational Rose, Argo UML, Microsoft Visio, and Visual paradigm for UML, Enterprise Architect.
- Version Control: Git, Visual Source Safe
- BI Tools: PowerBI, Tableau
- CMS: Joomla, WordPress



SELF LEARNING

- C# Best Practices for Developers (Lynda)
- Learning C# Algorithms (Lynda)
- Learning ASP.NET Core (Lynda)
- .NET Developer on Microsoft Azure (Pluralsight)
- Azure Fundamentals (Microsoft Azure Docs)
- Power BI pro Essential Training (Lynda)
- Programming Foundations: Data Structures (Lynda)

- C# Design Patterns (Lynda)
- Learning S.O.L.I.D Programming Principles (Lynda)
- Angular 7 The Complete guide (Udemy)
- Build a Real-world App with ASP.NET Core and Angular 2 (Udemy)
- Advanced SQL for Data Scientists (Lynda)



ACHIEVEMENTS

- Global Delivery Center: Client Delight Team Award, IQVIA, 2017
- 3rd at ByteKnight Cyber-Security Challenge, OWASP, 2012
- Three times Chess champion, FCC, 2003, 2005, 2007
- Primary Scholarship, BD Govt., 2000



INTEREST

- DevOps
- Software architecture and design
- Artificial Intelligence

- Sports
- Traveling
- Reading

CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Attended in different programming contest
- Organized various cultural and sporting events
- Attended in different sports/gaming competition

COMMUNICATION SKILLS

- Fluent in English and Bengali, both verbal and written
- Strong command on presentation, report writing and public speaking
- Skilled in all sorts of business and commercial correspondence



REFERENCES

Shah Mostafa Khaled

Associate Professor khaled@univdhaka.edu Institute of Information Technology University of Dhaka

Syedur Rahman

Software Architect & Lead DevOps, syedur@dev.panth.com The Jaxara IT Ltd., Dhaka, Bangladesh